Arash Pourhabibi-Zarandi

pourhabibi@cse.shirazu.ac.ir http://arash.pourhabibi.info +98 (939)343-9383

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Distributed Systems, Cloud Computing & Software Engineering

My research interest relies on cloud computing and its abstraction levels from top to bottom; how to efficiently build a Software as a Service (SaaS) and deploy it on a cloud provided platform (PaaS) which is running on virtualized hardware (IaaS). The usage of new multi-core CPUs and modern GPUs as the infrastructure of cloud and distributed computing; and NoSQL systems as the backbone of its big data computations.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Software Engineering

Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran

2013 - 2015 (Expected)

- Accepted in the M.Sc. program without university entrance exam, as the exceptional student in the department.
- Ranked First: Achieving the highest GPA (19.89/20) among all M.Sc. students.
- Related Courses: Advanced OS, Advanced Computer Architecture, Multicore Programming, Parallel Algorithms, Grid Computing, Software Architecture, Text Mining

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering) Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran

2009 - 2013

June 2013

- Ranked First in CS related Courses: Achieved the highest GPA in CS courses (18.88/20) among all B.Sc. students.
- Ranked Third: Achieved the third highest overall GPA (17.56/20) among all B.Sc. students.

Diploma in Mathematics and Physics

National Organization for Development of Exceptional Talents(NODET), Kerman, Iran 2005-2009

AWARDS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Ranked **second** in the **Java** section of the First Iran Programming Skill Challenge, held by Sharif University of Technology and Tehran University's Faculty of Entrepreneurship.

Summer 2014

Accomplishment with Distinction in University of Maryland's online **Developing Innovative Ideas** for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship course with score of 100% Taught by Dr. James V. Green at Coursera

January 2015

Accomplishment in IIT Delhi's online **Web Intelligence and Big Data** course

Taught by Gautam Shroff at Coursera

December 2013

Accomplishment in UC Berkeley's Online SaaS I and SaaS II courses with scores of 94% and 92% Taught by David Patterson, Armando Fox at EdX

Summer 2013

Awarded as the **Best Undergraduate Student** in Computer Engineering
Shiraz University

Nominated for the **Best Mobile Application** for S.A.H.A. (iPhone Application for Phone Bill Management) at the First Iran Mobile Innovation Awards, held by Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran.

February 2012

Stanford's Online Introduction to Databases course with score of 294/323

Taught by Jennifer Widom

October - December 2011

LANGUAGES

Persian (Maternal)

English (Advanced) - TOEFL iBT score: 100(R:29, L:27, S:23, W:21)

October 2013

EXPERIENCE

Shiraz University

2010 - 2013

Member of CSE Department Network Administration Team, proposed and implemented new services for the department such as CMS (Content Management System).

Internship at Shiraz University CERT Center (ShirazAPA)
Programmer and Researcher on "Update Manager" project.

under the supervision of Dr. Farshad Khunjush

2010 - 2011

Freelance Java and iOS Programmer and founder of Mobile Programming group in Shiraz University

SELECTED PROJECTS

More information on these and my other projects is available on my homepage.

• BigKernel (M.Sc. Thesis)

Present

It's a joint research project with Reza Mokhtari under supervision of Prof. Michael Stumm at the University of Toronto. It's based on a scheme, named BigKernel, that provides pseudo-virtual memory to GPU applications and is implemented using a 4-stage pipeline with automated prefetching to optimize CPU-GPU communication and optimize GPU memory accesses. It's based on a proposed compile-time system that takes a BigData application as input and modifies it to automate the CPU-GPU data communications and improve the overall performance of the application. We are developing the compiler tool using the LLVM infrastructure.

• Software Transactional Memory on GPUs

Present

A research project with my colleague Ali Faraji regarding the parallelism problems dealing with data access on Graphics Processing Units. We are trying to implement and analyse pure Software Transaction Memory environment on GPUs in order to evaluate the efficiency from both performance and cost views. The projects output will be a library which helps GPU programmers to take the abstraction to a higher level. All common problems like lock handling, race conditions and deadlock will be handled automatically using the ideas which originally came from Database Management Systems and lead to a Hardware Transactional Memory on Intel Haswell CPUs.

• Pure P2P File Sharing Application Written in Java

Fall 201

In this application each peer can add other peers to its peer list and then asks its peer list for a file name. Each peer then replies whether he has the file or not. If the file is available the asking peer will receive the file from others. For writing this application, I first wrote a general purpose P2P Framework in Java then I wrote a file sharing application on top of it which uses an UDP flooding feature for finding peers.

• Online Judge System with Code Similarity Written in Java

Fall 2010

The goal was to create a system for online exams of C Programming course, so that the students can see the questions and submit their answers over the network and to self-check their answers. It uses the code similarity algorithms used in Plagiarism Detecting Applications to calculate how much the submitted code is similar to the one that the instructor had submitted.

• Steganography Written in C

Spring 2010

Its a text based menu-driven application written in C and it can hide a text file in a Bitmap image and extract it back from the image. It's based on the paper Adaptive Data Hiding in Edge Areas of Images With Spatial LSB Domain Systems and can hide up to 15 bits in each pixel of an image.

PUBLICATIONS • Design and Implementation of a scheme for BigData Processing on GPU

In Preparation

• Official Persian translation of "Engineering SaaS: An Agile Approach Using Cloud Computing" written by Armando Fox and David Patterson. It is going to be published soon by the help of Nima Towhidi and under supervision of Dr. Ahmad Towhidi.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Python, C, Java SE, SQL, Objective-C, Ruby, Shell Scripting Programming Models, Platforms & Frameworks: LLVM, MPI, OpenMP, CUDA, PThreads,

MapReduce, Ruby On Rails

Operating Systems: OS X, Linux, Windows

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Grid Computing

• Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Gholamhossein Dastgheybifard

Spring 2014

Software Architecture

o Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Mostafa Fakhrahmad

Spring 2014

GPU Programming

• Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Farshad Khunjush

Fall 2013

Design & Implementation of Programming Languages

o Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Mohammad-Reza Mousavi

Spring 2013

Database Laboratory

o Teacher supervised by Dr. Ali Hamzeh

Spring 2015, Spring 2014, Spring 2013

Fundamentals of Computer and Programming Using Python

o Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Ahmad Towhidi

Fall 2012

• Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Farshad Khunjush

Fall 2010

Principles of Programming Using C

o Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Ali Hamzeh

Spring 2012, Spring 2011

Advanced Programming Using Java

o Teacher Assistant supervised by Dr. Ali Hamzeh

Fall 2011

EXTRA-**CURRICULAR** ACTIVITIES

BreakTime In University

Summer 2010 - Summer 2014

BreakTime In University is a three-day conference consists of up to 50 different workshops which has been held by a group of university students from the summer of 2007 at Shiraz University. Around 300 talented high schoolers attend this event every summer and its goal is to help them know their skills and potentials, how they can be creative and innovative and how they can work better in teams. In addition to these, they become familiar with university, different study majors and how to become successful researchers. I had the chance to be a part of the organization team for five years and had different responsibilities in preparation and program committees.

Internet and Technical Services Assistant

16th CSI International Symposiums on Computer Architecture & Digital Systems and Artificial Intelligence & Signal Processing, Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran May 2012

REFERENCES

Dr. Farshad Khunjush (khunjush@cse.shirazu.ac.ir)

Prof. Armando Fox (fox@cs.berkelev.edu)

Last Update: March 2015